Finding Aid for the Ruth St. Denis Papers LSC.1031
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 5: Media, 1900s-1960s
  - Subseries 5.3: Reel to reel tapes
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 3, undated (Box 156, Folder 3)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 4, undated (Box 156, Folder 4)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 6, undated (Box 156, Folder 5)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 7, undated (Box 156, Folder 6)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 8, undated (Box 156, Folder 7)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 9, undated (Box 156, Folder 8)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 10, undated (Box 156, Folder 9)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 11, undated (Box 156, Folder 10)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 12, undated (Box 156, Folder 11)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 13, undated (Box 156, Folder 12)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 14, undated (Box 157, Folder 1)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 15, undated (Box 157, Folder 2)
    - "An Unfinished Life" part 16, undated (Box 157, Folder 3)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 157, Folder 4)
    - Riverside art speech, Mission Inn, 1959 March 4 (Box 157, Folder 5)
    - Stockton, December 25, no year (Box 157, Folder 6)
    - Howard speech, undated (Box 157, Folder 7)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 157, Folder 8)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 157, Folder 9)
    - Buddha's birthday and divine dance class, undated (Box 157, Folder 10)
    - Forrest Phoenix college dinner, undated (Box 157, Folder 11)
    - Storrer, Thank JD, 1958 (Box 157, Folder 12)
    - Lecture, California State College, Los Angeles, CA, 1964 May 22 (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - Poems and essays by Ruth St. Denis, 1962 August 25 (Box 158, Folder 2)
    - Stockton - large group teaching speech by St. Denis; Divine Dance, Lesson No. 7, 1957 December 2-3 (Box 158, Folder 3)
    - Poems, dramatic readings with other people, undated (Box 158, Folder 4)
    - Miss Ruth and Ted Shawn, 1965 March 2 (Box 158, Folder 5)
    - Speech, 1961 September 10 (Box 158, Folder 6)
    - Mrs. Vigo, undated (Box 158, Folder 7)
    - Thanksgiving party and Speech from UCLA, 1964 August 3 (Box 158, Folder 8)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 158, Folder 9)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 158, Folder 10)
    - Poems, undated (Box 158, Folder 11)
    - Freedom, 1959 December 28 (Box 158, Folder 12)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 159, Folder 1)
    - Miss Ruth birthday, undated (Box 159, Folder 2)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 159, Folder 3)
    - Essays and poetry, 1958 (Box 159, Folder 4)
    - Shinto, undated (Box 159, Folder 5)
    - Temple City, "Pow-wow", 1961 September 9 (Box 159, Folder 6)
    - Kwanon performance, undated (Box 159, Folder 7)
    - St. Denis dance prose, undated (Box 159, Folder 8)
    - "Omika," intro to "Temple" dialogues, and poems, undated (Box 159, Folder 9)
    - Wigman party, 1958 April 18 (Box 159, Folder 10)
    - Gleason ranch, 1957 (Box 159, Folder 11)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 159, Folder 12)
    - Essay, April 25, no year (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 160, Folder 2)
    - Sales talk about little tape machine, undated (Box 160, Folder 3)
    - "Check and copy", 1963 October 29 (Box 160, Folder 4)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 160, Folder 5)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 160, Folder 6)
    - Ruth St. Denis and Norman Borine, 1961 August 12 (Box 160, Folder 7)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 160, Folder 8)
    - Ruth St. Denis speech, 1964 February 16 (Box 160, Folder 9)
    - Lesson, choir, undated (Box 160, Folder 10)
    - "You made me love you", undated (Box 160, Folder 11)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 160, Folder 12)
    - Freedom, undated (Box 160, Folder 13)
    - Border poem, 1963 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 161, Folder 2)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - Unlabeled reel, 1958 April (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - Dialogue: Miss Ruth and Tang, 1952 (Box 161, Folder 5)
    - Oman Padma Oum, undated (Box 161, Folder 6)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 161, Folder 7)
    - Queens' College, 1963 November 3 (Box 161, Folder 8)
    - Border poems, 1963 (Box 161, Folder 9)
    - Magnificant, Vox, undated (Box 161, Folder 10)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 161, Folder 11)
    - Story drama speech, 1962 December 2 (Box 161, Folder 12)
    - Aubry and Miss Ruth, Mad woman, undated (Box 162, Folder 1)
    - Ruth St. Denis choir lesson, undated (Box 162, Folder 2)
    - Entertainment for beloved, undated (Box 162, Folder 3)
    - Dialogue Skipper and Ruth St. Denis, undated (Box 162, Folder 4)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 162, Folder 5)
    - Bywaters interview, 1961 August 4 (Box 162, Folder 6)
    - Ruth St. Denis, Nautch talk, undated (Box 162, Folder 7)
    - Arcadia pageant, 1957 (Box 162, Folder 8)
    - Stockton, 1957 December 3 (Box 162, Folder 9)
    - TV Hervey, 1963 (Box 162, Folder 10)
    - Service, 1952 March 4 (Box 174, Folder 1)
    - Freedom, undated (Box 174, Folder 2)
    - Ruth St. Denis interview with Howard Nelson, 1962 (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - Phil's film, 1963 December 6 (Box 174, Folder 4)
    - Miss Ruth lecture, Stockton, 1957 December 2 (Box 174, Folder 5)
    - Taped speech, Barbara Flushing, 1964 May 10 (Box 174, Folder 6)
    - Stockton lecture, 1957 December 2-4 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    - Miss Ruth birthday, 1965 January 20 (Box 174, Folder 8)
    - Ruth St. Denis and Skipper, undated (Box 174, Folder 9)
    - Miss Ruth speech, undated (Box 174, Folder 10)
    - Temple dialogue, 1964 (Box 174, Folder 11)
    - Unlabeled reel, undated (Box 174, Folder 12)
    - Professional tape, master, Gold Madonna, Ann Thompson McDowell, 1958 October 21 (Box 175, Folder 1)
    - Journal reading of 1932, 1963 November 3 (Box 175, Folder 2)
    - Persian rug, Bernie; Ravel scarf, unfinished; Javanese, unfinished, undated (Box 175, Folder 3)
    - Ruth St. Denis Day, Adelphi University, 1966 December 17 (Box 175, Folder 4)
    - Life, poems, 1964 January 4 (Box 175, Folder 5)
    - Border poems, dialogue, 1963 (Box 175, Folder 6)
- Series 6: Clippings, ephemera, and publications, 1920s-1960s
  This series contains clippings about St. Denis and from dance publications. There are also flyers and programs from her performances, pamphlets and advertisements about St. Denis's organizations, and invitations and membership information about those organizations.
  - Subseries 6.1: Clippings and publications, 1920s-1960s
    Contains newspaper and magazine clippings about St. Denis, as well as dance publications. Also includes scrapbooks of newspaper clippings.
    - Magazines and publications, 1920s (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Magazines and publications, 1930s (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - "How Beautiful upon the Mountain: A History of Jacob's Pillow" by Ted Shawn, 1943 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Magazines and publications, 1940s (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Magazines and publications, 1950s (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Ephemera, "Voice of Peace" vol. 1 no. 1, 1968 May (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Magazines and publications, 1960s (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Magazines and publications, 1960s (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Magazines and publications, 1960s (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Magazines and publications, 1960s (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Magazines and publications, 1960s (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Magazines and publications, 1960s (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Magazines and publications, undated (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Magazines and publications, undated (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1920s (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1930s (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1930s-1960s (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1930s (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1940s (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1950s (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper article on Ruth St. Denis, 1953 July 26 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1950s (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1950s (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Magazine clippings, 1926 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - "The Dance: Magazine of Stage and Screen", September 1930 (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Creative Dance Journal: Creative Dance News of the West, 1948 May-November (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - "100 American Women of Accomplishment, Harper's Bazaar 1967" (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - "The Pageant of the Pacific", undated (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1930s-1940s (Box 92, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1950s (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1950s (Box 92, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 92, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1960s (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - The Denishawn Magazine, 1925 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Dance Magazine, 1926 and 1928 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 6.2: Ephemera, 1920s-1960s
    Contains flyers, programs and advertisements from performances by St. Denis, as well as other dancers; pamphlets for dance programs and classes; and invitations to join St. Denis's organization, such as the Society of the Spiritual Arts and the Church of Divine Dance, and membership information about these organizations.
    - Pamphlets, 1920s (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets, 1930s (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets, 1940s (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlets, 1950s (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Pamphlets, 1960s (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlets, 1960s (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets, undated (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets, undated (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Flyers and programs, 1920s (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Flyers and programs, 1900s-1920s (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Flyers and programs, 1930s (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Flyers and programs, 1940s (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Flyers and programs, 1940s (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Theater Intime Programs collected by Dorothy Lee Tifal, 1948 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Flyers and programs, 1950s (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Flyers and programs, 1950s (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Flyers and pamphlets, 1950s (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Invitations and membership, 1930s-1940s (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Invitations and membership applications, 1940s (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Invitations and membership, 1960s (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Invitations and membership, undated (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Invitations and memberships, undated (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Advertisements, undated (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Misc ephemera, 1920s-1930s, 1950s-1960s (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Misc ephemera, undated (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Misc ephemera, undated (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Misc ephemera, undated (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Misc ephemera, undated (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Misc ephemera, undated (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera, 1925-1967 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera, undated (Box 92, Folder 11)
    - Flyers and programs, 1940s (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - Broadside by Vachel Lindsay, signed, undated (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - Ephemera, 1950s-1960s (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - Ephemera, 1961 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Ephemera, 1920s-1930s (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Ephemera, 1940s (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook of Society of Spiritual Arts Church materials, 1940s (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Ephemera, 1950s (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - Ephemera, 1960s (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Ephemera, undated (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Ephemera, undated (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - Flyers and programs, 1960s (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Flyers and pamphlets, 1960s (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Flyers and programs, 1960s (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Flyers and programs, 1960s (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Flyers and programs, 1960s (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - "The Golden Book of Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn", 1964 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Flyers and programs, 1960s (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Flyers and programs, 1960s (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Flyers and pamphlets, undated (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Flyers and programs, undated (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - Flyers and pamphlets, undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Flyers and programs, undated (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Flyers and programs, undated (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Flyers and programs, undated (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Ephemera, 1950s-1960s, undated (Box 151, Folder 5)
- Series 7: Books from personal library, 1880-1968 (Box 101, Box 102, Box 103, Box 104, Box 105, Box 106, Box 107, Box 108, Box 109, Box 110)
  Contains books from St. Denis's personal library, the majority of which focus on religion and spirituality. This series also includes some books written by St. Denis, as well as many books written by Mary Baker Eddy. St. Denis was very influenced by Mary Baker Eddy's writings, particularly in her belief that dance was both art and religion.
- Series 8: Business materials, 1920s-1960s
  This series contains financial, medical and legal materials, inventories of St. Denis's possessions, and business notes and memos pertaining to performances, St. Denis's schedule, fundraising, contracts, and St. Denis's bequest.
  - Subseries 8.1: Financial materials, 1920s-1960s
    Includes bank statements, receipts, and fund raising materials.
    - Financial materials: Receipts, Denishawn House fundraising letter, 1919-1930s (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - Financial materials: Receipts, financial statements, 1940s (Box 97, Folder 10)
    - Financial materials: Receipts accepted by Elyse Robert, 1940s (Box 98, Folder 1)
    - Banking books (1 of 2), late 1950s-early 1960s (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Banking books (2 of 2), late 1950s-early 1960s (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Financial materials, 1950s (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Bank account information, 1950s (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Financial materials: Ledgers, 1950s (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Financial materials, 1950s (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Financial materials: Receipts, 1950s (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Financial materials: Bank statements and receipts, 1961 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Financial materials: Macy's receipts and Chemical Bank deposit receipts, 1961 (Box 99, Folder 2)
      No Subnote Content
    - Financial materials: Macy's receipts, 1961 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Financial materials: Receipts and financial statements, 1960 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Notes on grants, 1966 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Financial materials, 1960s (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Financial materials, 1960s (Box 99, Folder 7)
      Includes fundraising materials
    - Financial materials, 1960s (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Financial materials, 1960s (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Financial materials, 1960s (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Financial materials, undated (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Financial materials, undated (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Financial materials, undated (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 8.2: Medical materials, 1920s-1960s
    Contains medical records, recommendations from doctors, and dietary recommendations.
    - Medical documents, 1920s, 1960s, and undated (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 8.3: Legal materials, 1920s-1960s
    Includes contracts and St. Denis's bequests.
    - Legal materials, 1920s-1960s, undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Legal notes and will, 1965 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 8.4: Business notes and memos, 1920s-1960s
    Includes memos and meeting notes related to St. Denis's schedule and performances.
    - Informal business notes, 1920s-1940s (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Informal business notes, 1950s (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Informal business materials, 1950s (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Informal business materials, 1950s (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Informal business materials, 1960s (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Informal business notes, 1960s (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Informal business notes, 1960s (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Notes on lecture film project, 1960s (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Informal business notes, 1960s (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Informal business materials, 1960s (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Informal business materials, undated (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Informal business materials, undated (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Informal business notes, undated (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Informal business notes, undated (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Formal business materials, 1930s-1940s (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Formal business materials, 1950s (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Formal business materials, 1950s (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Formal business materials, 1960s (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Exhibit ideas, 1960 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Outlines for exhibits, 1966 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Formal business materials, 1960s (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Formal business materials, undated (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Formal business materials, undated (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Business materials: Legal performer agreement, 1950s (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - Informal business notes, 1960s (Box 125, Folder 15)
    - Business materials: Professional Educational Presentations Program at the New York State Council on the Arts, 1968-1969 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - Informal business notes, undated (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - Formal business materials: Ruth St. Denis School of Dancing Agreement, written notes, and Indenture, 1918-1963 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Business materials, 1920s-1940s (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Business materials, 1930s-1940s (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Business materials, 1950s (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Business materials, 1950s (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - Business materials, 1960s (Box 127, Folder 6)
    - Bequests, 1963 June (Box 127, Folder 7)
    - Business materials, 1960s (Box 127, Folder 8)
    - Business materials, 1960s (Box 127, Folder 9)
    - Business materials, 1960s (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - Business materials, 1960s (Box 128, Folder 2)
    - Business materials, 1960s (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - Business materials, 1960s (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - Business materials, 1960s (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - Business materials, 1960s (Box 128, Folder 6)
    - Business materials, 1960s (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Book list, undated (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Ruth St. Denis book listing, undated (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Business materials, undated (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - List of books at Homestead California, undated (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Business materials, 1950s-1960s, undated (Box 151, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 8.5: Lists and inventories, 1920s-1960s
    Includes inventories of St. Denis's possessions.
    - Lists and inventories, 1930s-1950s (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - List of materials for folio, 1953 (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Inventories, 1959 November (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Lists and inventories, 1960s, undated (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Lists and notes, 1940s-1960s (Box 127, Folder 3)